Kostadis Roussos: Hello Hello Nikhil
Nikhil: Hey folks, what's up?
Kostadis Roussos: Dude, that is a very nice headshot of you.
Nikhil: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm almost like, who is this failure? That's not him.
Nikhil: I had this picture always.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I know, but I just noticed
Nikhil: Okay, yeah, I was turning on the video, so you might not be able to see.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, okay. All right, okay. DoomZoom.us Let me just see, where am I? All right, all 20.
Kostadis Roussos: Come on, sign in. So when like COVID happened, Roll20 got slammed.
Nikhil: Vanir Kugelsnacht
Kostadis Roussos: When COVID started...
Nikhil: Right, right, yeah, yeah, yeah, oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: like what happened was that like playing on digital tabletop was kind of this boutique thing that pretty much nobody did and then cove it happened and now everybody now it's become like the way you play the game there's people who think that that's bad there are people who think that's good i don't know to me it's just neither here nor there
Nikhil: I don't know, I'd like to, you know, I like the feel of more from the characters as a role in the dice, so I would still prefer for something, you know, this I've got a really good story, so something that has a good story, I feel it should be in person.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I agree. Anyway, I shared with you the Syrinscape link. Let's see if this time it works. Alright.
Nikhil: Are you playing something?
Kostadis Roussos: no no I'm not yet I'm sorry well done I'm just like I love this tool but like it the UI that I love that the audio it's done but it's like sometimes see this will work
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Nikhil: Yes, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: You can hear it? Oh, it makes one of us. Okay, you can hear it, which is odd. Now I can't. Hm, alright. Uh, sound settings. Okay. Oh, I see the problem. Let me just put that over here.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, can you hear it?
Nikhil: Yes, I can hear you.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent. Alright. Okay.
Nikhil: So the map...
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Nikhil: It's very faint. Let me try increasing the volume.
Kostadis Roussos: You can adjust the volume if you want.
Nikhil: Okay, perfect.
Kostadis Roussos: all right all right let's go here okay initiative all right all right so can i show you how you can roll initiative so i don't oh oh did i already roll initiative no i don't did i roll initiative I'm sure there's...
Nikhil: I think we did.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Did we? Yeah. Now, I don't think I rolled for you. You didn't roll initiative. Or if you did, I don't...
Nikhil: I did die. I got a bad initiative. It was a 4.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you did get a 4. Okay.
Nikhil: Wait. Okay, let's do it again.
Kostadis Roussos: Why don't you roll, I don't think, I think that monsters rolled for initiative, but I'm not entirely convinced you rolled for initiative.
Nikhil: So you were going to show me how to do that or?
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just, let me just make sure, alright, give me one second, alright, so if you click on, if you click on your character first in roll 20, and then roll initiative, it'll pop the, it'll put the initiative directly in there.
Nikhil: I click on a character in the map
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and then click on initiative in your enroll in D&D Beyond. It'll do the right thing
Nikhil: Twenty
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so your initiative should have appeared in the uh... Yes.
Nikhil: Oh, this is interesting. So I click on the character and do whatever the action here.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you very much.
Nikhil: and so on and so forth.
Kostadis Roussos: That way. All right All right, okay, so this skeleton over here attacks first
Kostadis Roussos: All right, it picks up its short bow and fires a bolt at you. That misses spectacularly. So, your turn. Who's turn is it?
Nikhil: My turn, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, yeah. Sister Maela shouts, If you have a mace, now would be a good time to use it.
Nikhil: I don't have a mace, I don't have a mace I'll use the Vex
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Alright. Okay.
Nikhil: So I'm rolling for the first turn.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a miss. Next attack.
Nikhil: Thank you for watching!
Kostadis Roussos: All right, would you roll the, ooh, that's a 20. All right, roll for damage.
Nikhil: Why is the creek not working?
Kostadis Roussos: Because sometimes it doesn't, because it hates you that way.
Nikhil: How do I click? Ok. Damage. Ok, I'm rolling for damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Eight points, eight points. Ooh, that's not very good, but that's better than nothing.
Nikhil: Wait, 8 points of damage does nothing?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I mean it does, it does, but not enough.
Nikhil: Shit, all good.
Kostadis Roussos: There you go. Okay. I'm assuming you attacked this guy because that's the only guy you could use your sneak attack bonus for. Alright. Is there anything I can do here? Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, um, do-do-do-do-do, okay, so where were we, roll 20, okay, hmm, alright, so where were we, okay, the skeleton.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, this skeleton takes a shot at Pip.
Nikhil: There's a bunch of fun.
Kostadis Roussos: this one here with his short bow and that is a i think that's a mess
Kostadis Roussos: It's a summer class. Yep, that's a mess. All right, Sister Maela.
Nikhil: Thanks for watching!
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela walks in front and will use her ability to turn undead
Nikhil: Go on ahead.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. She goes, watch this.
Nikhil: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, okay, just do something here.
Kostadis Roussos: The other side kick.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Actually, they can't turn undead? That's weird. Hold on. Okay, fine. I've declared they should be able to turn undead. Clerics that can't turn undead are kind of pointless. All right. Give me a second. Sorry, I just realized I did something with the definition of the maela that didn't work. Turn undead, fifth edition, second level.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so it's, uh, right, so it's, uh, she stands up in front, she stands in front of, uh, the monsters and says, Begone! In the name of my Dwarven God. Alright. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, oh no no, that's not, that's not the damage, that's their, that's their, what's their spell DC, what's their wisdom, their wisdom is plus two, plus four, twelve, alright, so, two of them failed their saving throws, let's see, one, two, three, four, that's three, this guy failed, alright, he is frightened.
Kostadis Roussos: And then this guy's also frightened. Alright, so you see the two ones with the little dots? They've been frightened, so they're not going to attack you. Hopefully.
Nikhil: No damage, just frightening?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, they're frightened. So as long as you don't attack them, they're not going to attack you, and they're going to try to get away as far as they can from Sister Maela.
Nikhil: Nice to see you.
Kostadis Roussos: What? Good work, Sister Maela. She goes, of course it's good work. That's who I am. All right. Okay. This is, this is, this skeleton runs through here, opens the door and runs through here.
Nikhil: So, let's run.
Kostadis Roussos: yeah okay this skeleton on the other hand attacks Zenvon with his short sword and does 11 points of damage hold on hold on
Nikhil: Did you just say 11 points?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I said 11 points. Alright. Are you okay?
Nikhil: Yeah, no, no, I mean like 11. I just have got like 15 points.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, how many hit points do you have left?
Nikhil: Orr
Kostadis Roussos: All right, well, Sister Maela is going to have to heal you next. All right, um, B.I., uh, P.I.P., P.I.P., all right, what does P.I.P. do, P.I.P. uses, all right, so P.I.P.
Nikhil: Let's start with Veyra.
Kostadis Roussos: It's Pip and then Veyra. It's Pip and then Veyra.
Nikhil: And also I don't see Veyra in the turn order.
Kostadis Roussos: She's right there.
Nikhil: Sorry, sorry, I see it, I see it, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: She's there. Alright, so Pip will attack the one you've injured, and kills it. He will use an action surge to attack the next one over here, and hits it for how much damage?
Nikhil: Thank you for watching! Don't forget to like, comment, and subscribe for more videos!
Kostadis Roussos: Seven, uh, six points of damage. Alright. Veyra has cast Magic Missile twice, but if ever there was a time to cast her last Magic Missile, this would be it.
Kostadis Roussos: So let's see how much damage does each bolt do. Three. She kills this guy with two, and wounds this, no, wounds this guy with three. Alrighty. Alright. This guy runs over here as well. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: the skeleton uh marches up to i guess hold on and then pip goes over here because uh to protect you a little bit so the skeleton charges at pip and attacks with his short sword uh and misses Princesses.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, he misses. Okay, Zenvon, you're up. You might want to use Nick this time.
Nikhil: Nick is possible with the scimitar. Yes, I'll use the scimitar.
Kostadis Roussos: That way you can attack and disengage.
Nikhil: Yes It's a 10.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a miss. Roll again for your second attack.
Nikhil: Good night, everyone.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit. All right, damage. I'm assuming you moved over here. Damage?
Nikhil: damage 4 plus 5 12 points
Kostadis Roussos: Ooh, nice! You killed it!
Nikhil: Ooh! Yay!
Kostadis Roussos: all right there's only one skeleton left all right well they're mindless so i guess they will attack you because you're straight ahead of them all right oh they uh do six points of damage and you are you let me ask you a question you can are you going to stay there are you going to move out of the way
Nikhil: I'm gonna move back. I'm just at four points of damage so...
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you would move back right? So why don't you move somewhere else?
Nikhil: Okay, I'll move myself up and come back here.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so I guess he'll just attack Pip then for...
Nikhil: Sister Maela
Kostadis Roussos: No, Pip, because Pip's the closest. So Pip takes 6 points of damage. Alright, Sister Maela, I will cast Healing on you.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, let me just see what she does She will cast Cure Wounds What is Cure Wounds? Cure Wounds 2D form Can't remember what Cure Wounds is This is, um...
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Alright, 2d8 plus 2. 2d8 plus 2. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, hold on. She casted a 2d8. You get 10 more hit points, Pip. Leaving 10 more hit points. Alright. The skeleton continues to make chatter very far away.
Nikhil: The ones that run away.
Kostadis Roussos: yes they they they were still making they they run away all right pip
Nikhil: Pip!
Kostadis Roussos: Good?
Nikhil: No, I'm just telling you to click here then.
Kostadis Roussos: All right pip strikes the creature d20 plus four and he hits for d8 plus two five points of damage Veyra she's out of magic missiles but she can still do this that is a hit And that's it!
Kostadis Roussos: What did she do? She cast Firebolt.
Nikhil: Two points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: to be fair it does a lot less damage than the sound effects yes right this skeleton still is out of the way Zenvon you're up again
Nikhil: Yeah, that's true.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll use the shot score, I'll do the mix. Alright.
Nikhil: Should I move forward or can I attack from there?
Kostadis Roussos: You have to move forward. I mean, you have to be within five feet, right?
Nikhil: Okay, then...
Kostadis Roussos: but if
Nikhil: I'll do the link, okay, so put that in the bio.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll come here, I'll use the dagger
Nikhil: Nineteen? Twenty-four percent?
Kostadis Roussos: What? Roll for damage.
Nikhil: For eight points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, it dies. All right, hold on let's give you the
Nikhil: This sounds like Rocky Balboa music.
Kostadis Roussos: What? This sounds like the Rocky Balboa music, you know, the Rocky movie, when he... Have you seen it? Okay. Yeah, yeah, no, I've seen it. Yeah. Alright. So, where would you like to go next? So...
Nikhil: So the bottom east door is where the skeletons
Kostadis Roussos: Ember and I are off. Hold on, hold on. Ember and I are going. And the English, as is tradition, are taking out their frustrations on the French. I see. Ouch. It's 4-0. I see. Ouch. Somebody decided to come play a third place game and somebody decided they had better things to do. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay Zenvon let me just let me just remind you where you're here uh this is the three this is uh the Tresender crypts uh it had there are three large stone sarcophagi um and there's these false columns do you want to inspect the sarcophagi or do you want to go through the um
Kostadis Roussos: Or do you want to look at the various slids?
Nikhil: So, both of the skeletons ran through the open door at the bottom.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil: So first we'll inspect the coffins and then go to the same door where the other two skeletons ran away
Kostadis Roussos: okay so while you're doing that as you're as you're digging through that you find yourself in one of the one of the
Kostadis Roussos: As you're doing that, the two skeletons appear. Sister Maela goes, Huh, apparently they do, they don't, they stop being afraid.
Nikhil: Huh. Okay. I thought I'll deal with them in the next room, but...
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, but what you notice is that now in the brighter light they see that you're wearing red cloaks and choose not to attack you.
Nikhil: Where did the light come from?
Kostadis Roussos: While you were looking for things, remember, you can't see in the dark. Look, they weren't supposed to attack you before because you were wearing red cloaks, but I forgot, so I'm doing it now.
Nikhil: Cool, so they're not gonna attack and we'll still open the...
Kostadis Roussos: yeah they don't care as long as long as long as you're not doing anything as long as you don't attack them they won't attack you so there's kind of sitting just over here standing guard against anybody who might be a might be a bad guy might might and might not be the right leader might not be a red cloak since you're I didn't I missed that detail about the fact that red cloaks don't get attacked by the In the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Kostadis Roussos: caught the skeleton so consider this a uh so there's a jeweled gold bracelet worth 140 gold piece which lies among the bones in the sarcophagus containing the human female remains so let's just add that to the story notes where are we writing that up
Kostadis Roussos: Wherever we're keeping track of our treasure, we should put it there.
Nikhil: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Is it, is it in, is it?
Nikhil: Storybots, Storybots
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, 140 gold pieces, room 5, alright, room 6, room 4 rather, okay, there you go, alright, okay
Kostadis Roussos: As you're digging through that, you do hear some noise coming from the north-eastern door.
Nikhil: Please control. Okay. Mm-hmm. So...
Kostadis Roussos: Do you wanna go listen?
Nikhil: Have we gotten all the...
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, you've gotten all the loot from here.
Nikhil: Okay, then yes, I'm gonna go...
Kostadis Roussos: Luzon, Or.
Nikhil: What's happening at the door?
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay.
Nikhil: I'm rolling Investigation
Kostadis Roussos: um okay uh sorry i was trying to see if i had hold on i don't have it uh here we go that's what oh that one doesn't work either all right anyway so i was just curious if they had anything
Kostadis Roussos: So what you hear is essentially people, you hear people screaming, please help us, please help us!
Nikhil: I think they've been captured.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, as if they're captives.
Nikhil: We can deal with them later.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela says, Boss, I think we should help the helpless, you know, we're the good guys, remember?
Nikhil: Well, I'll do this for you, Sister Maela.
Kostadis Roussos: She got... She what? She got...
Nikhil: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, all right, do you want to open the door or do you want to have Pip open the door?
Nikhil: I will open the door.
Kostadis Roussos: you will open the door all right let's see hold on you open the door so because of all the noise you guys made they were ready for there turns out there were some bad guys ready for you all right but nobody is surprised because they are truly rolled awfully okay Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, Zenvon, you step inside, and you see, uh, the, you see the following. This long room is partitioned into three areas, with iron balls,
Kostadis Roussos: Wall bars walling off the north and south filthy straw lines the floors of these cells the hinged doors of which are secured by chains and padlocks a pair of human women are held in the cell to the south while human a human boy is confined to the north all right pair of human are held in the soil to the north while a human boy sorry he should be over there all right All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so um initiative, I guess Okay That they were waiting they were trying to surprise you, but they failed I'm trying to ambush you
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, let's see, okay, and we need these guys initiated, right?
Kostadis Roussos: That should be something. All right, Zenvon. Hold on.
Nikhil: I think Pip's is 15. What? Pip's number is 15.
Kostadis Roussos: No, his is 16. Oh, wait, did I not put him in? Hold on.
Nikhil: I see 10, 12, but not, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: No, why did, oh, I don't know, for some reason Pip's number did not, I must have done something here. Pip should be, um, Pip should be 12.
Nikhil: 5th is 12, Maela is 10
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, no, no, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on. Pip, uh, Maela is, uh, 15, and Pip is 12. I see two Pip. Okay. One is gone. Alright, let me just see, let me just have a look here.
Nikhil: Veyra, Seventeen
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, this is correct. Zenvon, Veyra has 17, Sister Maela has 15, Pip has 12.
Nikhil: Okay, so she has a plus one of the initiative? Yeah. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh no, she's got a plus 1 and Pip's got a plus 2. Alright, Zenvon, you're up.
Nikhil: Yes, um, I got the hang of it, it's okay. So, da-da-da-da-da.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you for watching!
Nikhil: Okay, I gotta be careful, so I'm gonna use my mic.
Kostadis Roussos: Um...
Nikhil: to attack the Redbrand
Kostadis Roussos: Number 1 and going back.
Nikhil: Move into the back room. So, you know, we'll go back here after attacking.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you're going to nick, you're going to use your nick.
Nikhil: yes i'm gonna use the dagger on him so i'll roll for that
Kostadis Roussos: He's got an armor class of 11.
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm going to put Pip over here. Alright.
Nikhil: Oh, damn it. Shit, it's just...
Kostadis Roussos: Five points of denture. Not exactly the best roll you could have done. Let me just make sure you can see the... Alright
Nikhil: I still have the second attack, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you do, you do, you do. Alright, done? Zenvon, are you going to stay there or are you going to move out of the way?
Nikhil: I'm going to move back.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm? Disengage.
Nikhil: Gelsen, Gelsen
Kostadis Roussos: All right. All right. The Redbrand attacks. All right. The Redbrand attack. And he does, what does he do? He attacks. All right. Which one is this?
Kostadis Roussos: That one, right? Okay. He steps over here and whacks Pip with his short sword and misses, but he uses that as an opportunity to come over here and move over here so that the next guy can attack. Alright. Veyra.
Kostadis Roussos: Where's Sister Maela? Where is she? Oh, there she is. She's right there. All right, Veyra. Veyra, what do you do, Veyra? Veyra's like, I don't like this! So she's, she's not very happy about this. What does she do? What are her spells?
Kostadis Roussos: oh she's run out of first level spells uh she is going to disengage and go over here all right
Nikhil: And I'm not going to spend any more time.
Kostadis Roussos: No, she can cast spells, but they're ranged spells, so she has a disadvantage, so she doesn't want to be with her four hit points killed by, you know...
Nikhil: Makes sense. Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Sister Maela, uh, Sister Maela, what does Sister Maela do? She's going to hit with her hammer, and that is a hit, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: uhhhh He does six points of damage alright the Redbrand ruffian number two he moves over here and he attacks
Kostadis Roussos: and he misses all right he will step over here Pip you're up what do you want Pip to do
Nikhil: I don't know what you mean, Pip. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You tell me what you want to do and then roll an attack. Yeah.
Nikhil: Uh, yeah, I wanna attack the guy in the crypt, in the crypt too, so...
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to talk to the guy in the crew, not the guy who's currently injured?
Nikhil: Both are the same guy, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, there's two people. There's a guy over here. Let me just show you. There's a guy in here, and there's a guy over here. There's like number one, number two, or number three.
Nikhil: The guy who was recently injured is the number one.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Yeah. I want them to attack the guide.
Nikhil: Number one.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Nikhil: Roll the beat, buddy.
Kostadis Roussos: Rule of d20 remember okay that is a hit he does six points of damages and kills him alrighty okay this guy charges a pip
Kostadis Roussos: and uh... Mrs. All right Zenvon, you're up.
Nikhil: I think I'm better at predicting hit or miss based on that.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Nikhil: Based on the numbers, I am trying to predict if it's a hit or a miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, he missed. Yes, yes. Hold on a second. No, no, no, hold on. No, yeah, he missed. He missed the...
Nikhil: One minute, I'll just get something. I want to do this.
Kostadis Roussos: Tell me when you're back, yeah?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I'm here.
Nikhil: So, Neutanics gave this small baseball bat, so I thought of using this as a sword.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, okay.
Nikhil: Oh, that's my turn to attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil: Both of them are inside the room so I'll still use the mic to move forward
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you're going to move forward over here, and attack from over here. You can even go over here if you wanted to.
Nikhil: oh yeah yeah I'll go there and I want to come back to that room so I'm going to use a nick
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Nikhil: I'm just gonna use my dagger. That was... Okay, I can...
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit!
Nikhil: the damage seven points of damage yes
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Nikhil: Albrek, Albrek, Albrek,
Kostadis Roussos: Are you going to move back, or...?
Nikhil: I'm gonna go and buy a kiss.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, sounds good. Alright, Veyra steps over here, casts her fire spell, and hits four, which is that.
Kostadis Roussos: D10, sorry, and D10, for 8 points of damage, and the guy's down to 1 hit point, this time it did sound that way, alright, Sister Maela
Nikhil: Who's down by ten points? The number two or the number three?
Kostadis Roussos: Number three.
Nikhil: Three. All.
Kostadis Roussos: You should look like he's down to very few hit points.
Nikhil: No, there are no help bar on them, so...
Kostadis Roussos: There aren't? Oh, sorry, sorry. There you go.
Nikhil: Thanks.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Sister Maela. Sister Maela will cast, um... Okay. He blows the saving throw, so he takes five points of damage of Sacred Flame.
Kostadis Roussos: Is there a sacred flame sound effect? No, there isn't. All right, so he takes sacred flame and dies. All right. Okay. This guy decides that, you know, he's had better days in his life. So he goes, one, disengages. Two.
Kostadis Roussos: Three, four, five, six. Alright, Pip turns to you. Are we chasing him boss or not?
Nikhil: Wait, where did he run away? Like, which way? Okay
Kostadis Roussos: Are you gonna chase him?
Nikhil: Not yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Do we want to chase him in case he calls any help or he's only one guy?
Nikhil: It's a good plan, I mean, it's quite positive. Okay, yeah, yeah. Two of us will chase them, and two of us...
Kostadis Roussos: Free these people.
Nikhil: So me and Veyra will go chase them, you guys free this
Kostadis Roussos: Pip turns. You're the guy with the fingers who knows how to open the locks. I'm the guy with the sword that knows how to kill people.
Nikhil: Yeah, okay, so you and Veyra can go behind the guy, me and Maela will help.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, okay. So Pip runs over here and attempts to thwack him with his sword. And he hits him for nine points of damage. Go Pip!
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Zenvon, rush in to open the locks.
Nikhil: Gryffindor
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see what you have to do to open these locks. Roll a 10 DC Dexterity check.
Nikhil: Dexterity check wait there's dexterity plus three and there's dex plus five both
Kostadis Roussos: Can we share my screen? Yeah, sure, share your screen.
Nikhil: You see there's this one here.
Kostadis Roussos: you know
Nikhil: That's Chiquit's air intro and this...
Kostadis Roussos: Could you go back to, what is that one, could you go to the DC5? Oh no no no, you want the save and throw one, that's the one you want.
Nikhil: Some dexterity saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep. Oh, was it a saving throw? Oh no, hold on, hold on, hold on. Hold on, no, hold on, it's not a saving throw, it's a skill check. So yes, you were, in fact, the top one is what you wanted.
Nikhil: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: All right you unlock the door uh the kid is very happy all right Veyra goes yay I've been saved all right Veyra kind of moves over here she casts her fire spell one more time a firebolt leaves her hands and hits four
Kostadis Roussos: Three points of damage. Alright, Sister Maela. She's come over here, so she's going to try to unlock the doors. And she too unlocks it.
Nikhil: You put it in a different category.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I pulled a different character. You're right. I meant Sister Maela. All right. Okay. The Redbrand Ruffian disengages again. Jumps.
Nikhil: Shit, okay, here I am again.
Kostadis Roussos: You're right over here. Alright. Pip, you're up.
Nikhil: Okay, now I've freed, me and Maela have freed both the...
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil: Welcome back.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, but it's Pip's turn, so do you want him to race after him?
Nikhil: Oh, yes, yes, Pip, great afternoon.
Kostadis Roussos: all righty all right
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Pip runs over here and unfortunately he triggers a trap. Yes, he falls into a pit.
Nikhil: I see, I hear some footsteps
Kostadis Roussos: And he takes, unfortunately, some damage. Fortunately, not very much, because I rolled very poorly. He takes three points of damage. And he's twenty feet down. Alright, Zenvon, you're up.
Nikhil: I'm gonna... since my job here is done, I'm gonna...
Kostadis Roussos: um hold on the the the the people go all right wait you're gonna just leave us here
Nikhil: Just stay here until I come back. It's not safe yet for you guys to move out.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, they're like, okay. All right
Nikhil: Okay, I'm gonna...
Kostadis Roussos: Why do... I see that Pip has fallen into the pit. Yes.
Nikhil: and I try to help him.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
Nikhil: Uh...
Kostadis Roussos: I'm assuming you have some rope or you can like help them climb out so that's what you're gonna do well actually you can you can I have a whip okay so I'm gonna use the whip as a rope to hand them
Nikhil: So that I can pull them off.
Kostadis Roussos: All right so I guess you can you can dash over here you pull him up all right that's what that's going to happen in his turn not now all right he'll be that's what you guys do he's over here he's climbed out all right Veyra comes over here
Nikhil: So my turn is done?
Kostadis Roussos: yeah your turn is done. Veyra has no ability to hit the guy but I guess if she moved let's say one two three she moves over here though she does right yeah I guess she does all right so she will attack she will fire her firebolt
Kostadis Roussos: And it misses entirely. It hits the wall instead of him. Alright. Sister Maela. That goes one. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so she's dashed over here. All right, the Redbrand ruffian goes one. Okay. Pip, you're up. Do you want to keep chasing him?
Nikhil: So we carefully move past the trap.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Nikhil: Um...
Kostadis Roussos: Now that you know where it is, you just like sort of walk around it.
Nikhil: around it yes yes and being more careful
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you very much.
Nikhil: Avoid any other traps.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Nikhil: Can I roll anything for that? I'm trying to...
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, you just, you, you, let me just see, uh...
Nikhil: I don't see anything related to that.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you don't have to roll anything. Once the trap is visible as it seems you can walk around it. Alright, so that's, you can come over here.
Nikhil: No, you're moving people.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I just, yeah.
Nikhil: Okay, okay, sure, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I'll...
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Zenvon, you're going to be right behind Pip.
Nikhil: Yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Sister Maela, Sister Maela is cast, I think her spell, this is her, this is her second Curley Wounds. Pip gets six hit points. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, do you want Pip to keep following, to keep going?
Nikhil: Yes, yes, I don't see anything where it's leading, but yes.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm not sure if I can see this right.
Nikhil: The Chosen is so big.
Kostadis Roussos: All right pip arrives over here
Kostadis Roussos: This door opens into a five-foot landing that is 15 feet above the large cellar with stone steps descending to the floor in two short flights. Another door stands beneath the stairs to the north. A large stone cistern occupies the western part of the room whose walls are lined with kegs and barrels. Alright, so just to make this a little bit more legible.
Kostadis Roussos: This is like at 15 feet, right? You see where that number 15 is? No, you can't, of course, because that would be too convenient. You see that number 15?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so that's 15 feet above the ground, right?
Nikhil: So this is the Roman episode.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so essentially there are these stairs that will go up to 15 feet and up to the top. You're in the cellar, if you can imagine.
Nikhil: Sildar the Spider, yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: okay and you see a door over here you see a door over there okay you may want to look around to see where you're you're the Redbrand ruffian went
Nikhil: Well, I don't have more visibility. I need to comment in the room.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wait, oh, your pip doesn't show, doesn't have visibility?
Nikhil: Wait, he does, he does, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: right
Nikhil: The stairs on the right side, but I can see the cellar, right? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Can you see that?
Nikhil: I can see the cellar, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: okay so that's all you so yeah so if you if all right there's a cistern
Nikhil: So there is like a water...
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, this this thing this thing over here is what's called a cistern All right
Nikhil: and i see some barrels okay one door on to the west
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Nikhil: Errrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrr
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, yeah, we'll go to...
Nikhil: and we don't see that guide yet
Kostadis Roussos: No, you don't. So you guys can come in and try to investigate to see if you can figure out where he's gone.
Nikhil: Yes, yes, roll an investigation.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. You don't you don't find them. You can... Veyra tries to help you, so why don't you roll again?
Nikhil: That should be fun.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, well with that you've figured out that he went over here
Nikhil: And we don't have access going upstairs to the 15th floor.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes you do, if you go up these stairs
Nikhil: Oh
Kostadis Roussos: You see did you see that here let me see let me see if this will help yeah you see this now
Nikhil: Right, right, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay? Okay. So what's your plan? Zenvon?
Nikhil: Okay, let's let's follow this guy
Kostadis Roussos: You're going to follow this guy? Yes. Alright. Are you going to try to listen to the door?
Nikhil: Yes, yes, as always, they went to the door, so roll an investigation.
Kostadis Roussos: 19. You hear some noises, some discussions, some murmuring behind the door. There's several
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so you hear people talking behind the door. All right.
Nikhil: This guy has told everybody.
Kostadis Roussos: There's my choice.
Nikhil: He leaves us no choice other than to attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Well you could always say that we've just killed all of your allies and you know maybe you want to like surrender and like we could take you prisoner and and investigate you I mean there's there are other options
Nikhil: But either way, I'm gonna open the door.
Kostadis Roussos: All right you open the door right this guy is actually over here all right what's your investigation roll your investigation
Nikhil: Why do I need to roll investigation?
Kostadis Roussos: they're hiding so I need to see if you okay you yeah you you you
Nikhil: We are hiding. Okay, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Right. So I need to see if you see them all. So you see everyone but this guy. Alright, you see...
Nikhil: The guy on to the south.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Yeah, he's hidden. The other guys you can see. Okay. Alright. So, um...
Nikhil: They do think that... Okay, yeah, go ahead, go ahead
Kostadis Roussos: Um, you're wearing a red cloak. They look at you and they go, they stop. They say, wait, you're one of us.
Nikhil: Yes. Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: And if they turn to...
Nikhil: Good.
Kostadis Roussos: They turn to the other redbrand. He goes, What do you mean they attacked you, man? Are you sure these are the guys that attacked you? This guy stands up and says, Do I look like I'm the kind of person who would lie? That is a killing machine! Kill him!
Nikhil: Okay, so it's my turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, so let me just explain to you the situation in case I haven't done it.
Nikhil: Oh yeah, that's good.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, okay, okay, great, alright.
Nikhil: so um yeah so he's saying uh the the Redbrand ran to the bandits and told that uh we attacked them
Kostadis Roussos: So here's what I'm gonna say
Nikhil: We are one of you guys like come on we have we all have the same dress and look at this guy this guy has turned a traitor he was uh trying to i i saw him letting in letting someone in so that's why i wanted to catch him and you know and eliminate him so he he's the bad guy
Kostadis Roussos: That is very clever. That is extremely clever. Roll your deception with advantage.
Nikhil: Thank you for watching!
Kostadis Roussos: All right, um, okay, let me see, I need some names now.
Kostadis Roussos: Hello, yes, I'm doing great, yes I did
Kostadis Roussos: What I wanted to ask you was if I could purchase a coupon to your car, let's say at the latest time of Sunday, and I can verify that. Oh, so you're going to be here actually out of the area for Christmas?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, alright thanks. Alright, thanks. Alright, thanks. Have a good rest of your day, take care. Are you still there? Hello? Mikiel, turn off your video. Hello?
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, I'm back. Oh, that's fine. Oh, that's fine. Just give me a second. All right. Let's see what happens. All right. All right, so, um...
Kostadis Roussos: One of the bandits, they all approach the other guy with their blades pulled out.
Nikhil: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, he's going to of course try to defend his honor. What did you roll for deception? Okay, he will try to roll a higher persuasion. And he fails. Meanwhile, after you freed everybody...
Kostadis Roussos: Two of the prisoners' voices are heard in the background.
Nikhil: Well, they're here.
Kostadis Roussos: What do you think they're gonna actually no they didn't I shake it back they're not because when they tried to escape what happened was the skeletons moved in to attack them and so now the skeletons are over here sorry
Nikhil: Can you comment to the system?
Kostadis Roussos: so they're not in there they're not in the cellar I just remembered they would be trapped in the prison because the skeletons once they saw them with no cloaks would start attacking them right so you're safe so you're saved all right Zenvon they've now surrounded him are you gonna
Nikhil: Are they going to come out?
Kostadis Roussos: Um, um, uh, okay, so he goes, so the bandit, whose name is Dosa Rook, um, says, um, says, uh,
Kostadis Roussos: About time somebody cleaned house, which I'm going to cut this rat into several pieces. The other bandit looks at him a little bit more carefully, goes, Hm, hm, traitor. Funny, nobody sent word down, but it's not very convincing when he's covered in blood and you're covered in blood.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, where am I? I'm going to have to go check, I'm going to have to go check this story to see if it's real. Are you going to let him check or are you going to try to bluff him again?
Nikhil: All right, I'll join with you. Let's go check. Let's confirm your suspicions and I'll try to take the bandit along with me. I'll go along with the bandit. So as soon as this guy is trying to steps into the cellar.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Nikhil: I'm gonna go behind him and attack him. That's the plan.
Kostadis Roussos: I figured as much, okay
Nikhil: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: um let me see okay so I'm assuming you're going to okay so he walks over here are you going to attack him are you gonna let the other the rest of your party attack him
Nikhil: The End
Kostadis Roussos: Because they can see you from there, remember.
Nikhil: Oh, I see. Okay, okay. No, as soon as he's out of the site, I want to attack.
Kostadis Roussos: but if you attack they will see you attack from where you currently are
Nikhil: Yeah, definitely gone from there.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but if you move out of the way, they might become suspicious.
Nikhil: Errm...
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just telling you.
Nikhil: Yeah, I'll let my team attack him.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, roll to, roll pick.
Nikhil: Okay, hold on. As soon as he is close to the stairs where Maela and Veyra are there, that's when I attack. Yes, exactly.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that's, okay, so roll, roll to hit, roll, um, pip, roll for pip to hit, alright, roll d20, plus 4, uh, 12, alright, that is a hit, roll for damage, d8, plus 2
Kostadis Roussos: Six points of damage. All right, all right, Veyra is very annoyed.
Nikhil: I don't see the bar owner this year.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, he don't see the bar in him. Uh-huh.
Nikhil: I need the bar.
Kostadis Roussos: You need the bar. Yes, sir. What am I doing? Okay, hold on. I'm clicking the wrong button.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Um, this guy gets to roll initiative. Okay, I'm gonna give him, I'm going to assume he was not expecting you guys to be attacked. Uh, Veyra tries to hit him with the dagger and misses. Sister Maela swings with her mace and misses. All right, he screams for help. Alp. What? .
Nikhil: Oh, I said oh no.
Kostadis Roussos: okay so we roll for initiative now the other two the other two go the the Redbrand says I told you these guys weren't to be trusted
Nikhil: And that's a huge show now.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, it is a shinsho.
Nikhil: I don't know if I can do this again.
Kostadis Roussos: What? So many characters!
Nikhil: That was useless.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, you did decide to backstab them. All right, Zenvon, you're up.
Nikhil: Okay, I roll for initiative right here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, uh, yeah, yes, I need you to roll for, oh, yes, I need you to, I rolled, I rolled for, you, you need to roll for initiative, roll your initiative, alright, right there, um, okay, Pip's got 20, um, Sister Maela's got 8.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra's got six, and Sister Maela's got four. All right, pip
Kostadis Roussos: hits the guy he met the guy he's hitting and kills him all right pip then goes one two three four five six and stands there ready to help you all right Zenvon you're up
Kostadis Roussos: Is that normal?
Nikhil: yes um sorry i'm just planning my strategy i can move forward um i'm gonna use the
Kostadis Roussos: Um
Nikhil: Nick the Lubex
Kostadis Roussos: Great.
Nikhil: Vex is when I can come back
Kostadis Roussos: No, Nick is when you can come back.
Nikhil: I'm going to use my dagger so I'm going to rolling for the hit what's the beat
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's a hit. Good. Damage. 12 points of damage. You killed him.
Nikhil: Let's flip back.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, just move your character back, right, you're gonna stand over there? All right, let's see what does this guy do?
Kostadis Roussos: Um, uh, Wick decides to attack the Redbrand and kills him. There he goes. What? He kills the Redbrand.
Nikhil: That was interesting actually. He actually believed that.
Kostadis Roussos: No, what he believes is, he goes, so look, I helped you, right? Yeah. And, you know, I, I, I didn't, I, you know, Glasstaff, man, he's like some scary shit, and I don't want to be here anymore, and I don't really want to die for him, so like,
Kostadis Roussos: I did you a solid and you're going to do me a solid and let me leave and pretend you never saw me.
Nikhil: A little bit of fairness in what you're saying, but we need you. Tell me more about Glasstaff and Spider and anything else that you know and we'll let you know.
Kostadis Roussos: All right our other thing is stay with us we have got a lot of gold coins silver pieces and a lot of you know treasure that we have earned through our adventure and you can get a share of it
Nikhil: Be a nice guy with us.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you want to recruit him?
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that was unexpected.
Nikhil: Thank you for watching! Don't forget to like, comment, and subscribe to our channel!
Kostadis Roussos: Um, okay. Okay, what does Wick know about Glasstaff? Let me just see. Give me a second. I need to think about it for a second. Was this unusual of recruiting someone? Uh, unexpected.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, it's his choice, he can either...
Nikhil: At which point, we don't know, I mean I cannot guarantee anything about if he can join us.
Kostadis Roussos: right okay so he goes Glasstaff he's a wizard not just a muscle with a title I've seen him drop a man with a spell no weapon drawn nobody messes with him twice
Kostadis Roussos: Then he goes, there's more than one, you know, this has got, this dungeon's got multiple levels, you already know this. Um, Wick's only ever been sent to the, I've only been sent to the subterranean part once to carry supplies, and I don't want to go back. Don't know what's there, but it's kind of wrong, there's something really wrong over there that messes with your head, I'm told. Then he...
Kostadis Roussos: so then you asked about who does he report to right he goes yeah Glasstaff answers to somebody i've overheard him complaining about orders from town and once about the boss's business but i mean i think it's somebody in Phandalin but i don't think i don't think Glasstaff's the big boss you asked about the black spar deer right
Nikhil: Black Spider
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he kind of flinches when you say it, but kind of as if he could feel something, you can see how uncomfortable that name makes him, but he doesn't know anything about it. Do you want to press him on the topic?
Nikhil: Yes, I want to question on the topic. So I roll Insight or Investigation, what do I do?
Kostadis Roussos: yeah roll the insight let me know just just roll intimidation
Nikhil: Intimidation. Oh yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: or Persuasion, whichever one you want.
Nikhil: Intimidation
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he goes, look dude, I just carry crates, alright? You start asking about the bass's boss, that's how people end up carrying less.
Nikhil: It's not good.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Nikhil: He's not giving me any information.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, because he's a low-level thug.
Nikhil: I know, I know. I'm still thinking what to do with him.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you told him that you have gold and treasure and you'd hire him, so he's kind of looking forward to that.
Nikhil: Okay, are you really interested to join us?
Kostadis Roussos: He's a role role in investigation or insight with advantage
Kostadis Roussos: Um, that said, okay. He says, yes. And, I'm trying to think what we're doing.
Nikhil: In order to trust you, you're gonna tell me all the secrets about this manor, like what's upstairs.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, Hilton. He goes, he goes, okay, he says yes, but you know he's lying. What you really, the impression you get is he's going to take whatever money you have and get out of Dodge as fast as possible.
Nikhil: What position he gives?
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Nikhil: Is that the impression he is giving?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, not that he'll betray you, but that he wants to get out of here.
Nikhil: Why are you taking our money?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you're offering it to him. He is a criminal.
Nikhil: I get it, yeah, yeah, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: all right I'm just telling you so so he takes your money and says of course I'm with you boss and then at his first opportunity he's gonna run away but you definitely do not get the impression that he's gonna try to backstab you he's basically looking at the money as a way to get out of here Greer.
Nikhil: Correct.
Kostadis Roussos: So what do you want to do with him? Do you want to give him the money and let him follow you? Or are you going to tie him up? Or let him run away? He's just one lowly thug.
Nikhil: This is such a tough choice. Hold on just a second. I want to, you know, try to get more information from him. So, I want to tie him up and, you know...
Nikhil: Shove his face into the cistern and get more information from him.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, the only additional piece of information he's kind of like really upset over this at this point in time um he's like shitting his pants and he says that there was this family the Dendrars that the Redbrands handled a while back I heard a while back
Nikhil: Dendrars? Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that's the family you guys rescued. Right, okay. Makes sense. Alright, he doesn't have anything else, so you're going to have to decide what you want to do with him. Okay, cool.
Nikhil: Yeah, I mean, I would prefer to attack him at this point instead of letting him run away.
Kostadis Roussos: all right so you're going to attack him all right roll for all right you kill him he he he is uh he's a poor defenseless guy he's dead uh we don't have we don't have to roll for uh combat okay and with that we are we are we we just have a couple we just have to explore these two rooms all right let's look into room number one
Nikhil: Did we get anything here? There are so many crates and barrels.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm about to check that, dude. Okay. Alright. Alright, so it turns out that the barrels have like food and things like that, right?
Kostadis Roussos: But you do notice a waterproof satchel which hangs from a submerged rope attached to the south wall of the cistern, about two feet below the water's surface. You find inside of it a satchel hidden, you find a satchel which contains a potion of healing and a potion of invisibility.
Kostadis Roussos: Motion of healing... put those... all right okay all righty all right and in the other room okay you find coin on the various bandits
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just show you what the coin is. I'll put it, I'll put... Alright, I'll just, okay. You find various coin here. Alright, do you want to go rescue the family that you just, that is currently being held by the zombies, by the skeletons?
Nikhil: What's a coin you said?
Kostadis Roussos: I put it in the chat I put it in the chat 16 silver piece 7 gold pieces is in one 12 gold pieces and 12 silver pieces and 5 gold piece in the other and the third holds 20 copper pieces 11 electrum pieces and two garnets worth 10 gold pieces each
Nikhil: What are you describing? Like 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, on the bodies of the bandits.
Nikhil: Oh, okay, okay, each one of them had these positions. Perfect, okay. So we are going to head back upstairs to...
Kostadis Roussos: downstairs you mean you're gonna go back over here right right to go rescue the to go rescue the family
Nikhil: That's upstairs, isn't it?
Kostadis Roussos: no it's it's downstairs okay let me just
Nikhil: The below one.
Kostadis Roussos: yeah so here is here this is zero feet all right that's zero feet and that's 15 feet and this is 10 feet all right
Nikhil: Upstairs.
Kostadis Roussos: Now so if you want to go to them you have to get this this doorway is at the zero feet Right and the the family that you you left is over here That make sense? All right
Nikhil: I'm going to move into this room.
Kostadis Roussos: move into that room all right the two skeletons are like poised at the door all right you're probably gonna have to kill them because they are they are definitely now like they're currently at the door and they're not moving from it
Nikhil: Yes, um, initiator or register?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, hold on, you may not have to, like, you can try to move, I mean, I'm just telling you, they're like, they're not
Nikhil: Thank you!
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see...
Nikhil: Something for my personal feeling, personal feeling is what it is.
Kostadis Roussos: No, my point is that you know that they weren't supposed to attack the folks with the red blinds so you could see if they're going to attack.
Nikhil: Okay, so yeah, looks like they might follow my orders or try to go forward and ask them to move out.
Kostadis Roussos: well they definitely don't ask they don't listen to you but they definitely don't attack you try to open the door
Nikhil: Yeah, I look at the clock.
Kostadis Roussos: Well you try to open the door and it's being held tight on the other side. You're going to have to tell the people that, you know, it's you because they're actually trying to keep the door closed.
Nikhil: oh okay yeah uh hey guys it's me i came back for you it's all safe now um i'm gonna let go of the door let me help you
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you walk inside, right? The skeleton sees you walk inside, and once it sees you walk inside, the skeleton decides that it's, you know, it goes back into its resting position. Okay. Perfect. I'm assuming you don't attack them as they move away.
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: alrighty okay and we shall stop here because it's four o'clock and we've been at it for an hour and a half
Nikhil: Okay, let's go.
Kostadis Roussos: Jeffon
Nikhil: Yes, I did. No cliffhanger this time, which is a good thing. What? No cliffhanger this time.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Nikhil: I mean I don't it doesn't have to be every time
Kostadis Roussos: All right. All right, sir. Take care
Nikhil: Thanks folks for this, take care, enjoy.
Kostadis Roussos: Bye-bye. Yeah, you too. Bye-bye.